欢迎来到信息检索课程。
Welcome to the information retrieval course.
我是黄如花。
I am Huang Ruhua.
来自武汉大学信息管理学院。
From the School of Information Management, Wuhan University.
是这门课程的主讲教授。
It is the lead professor of this course.
今天是这门课程的第一讲。
Today is the first lecture of this course.
问题便于大家更好的学习这门课程。
The problem is that everyone can learn this course better.
我觉得有必要。
I think it is necessary.
对这个课程的基本情况做一个简要的介绍。
Make a brief introduction to the basic situation of this course.
在这一节里面。
In this section.
我想和大家讨论以下四个方面的问题。
I want to discuss the following four aspects with you.
为什么要开设这门课程？
Why do you want to open this course?
对象是谁？
Who is the object?
第一次在课程网上线以后的效果如何？
What was the effect of the first time after the course online?
我们下一步有什么打算？
What are our plans for the next step?
首先是第一个问题。
The first is the first question.
为什么要开设信息检索这门慕课？
Why do you want to open an information retrieval course?
我想有三个方面的原因。
I think there are three reasons for this.
我本人从1996年开始。
I personally started in 1996.
一直从事信息检索课程的教学和有关的研究工作。
Has been engaged in the teaching of information retrieval courses and related research work.
在教学科研。
In teaching and research.
工作和生活当中。
Work and life.
获益良多。
gain much.
我希望与更多的人。
I hope to be with more people.
利用信息检索方面的一些体会。
Use some experience in information retrieval.
我们这门课程的。
We have this course.
授课的对象。
The subject of the lecture.
常听到有的同学说。
I often hear some students say.
这么课程确实给他们带来了很多的好处。
This course does bring a lot of benefits to them.
有助于他们提高其他的专业课程的学习。
Help them improve their learning in other professional courses.
那么，即使我们的学生毕业以后。
Well, even after our students graduate.
也认为这些内容。
Also think of these things.
对他们的工作。
For their work.
家住于沐可提供的这个平台。
I live in this platform provided by Muco.
能够有更多的。
Can have more.
或者是学员。
Or a student.
这是第二个原因。
This is the second reason.
第三个原因呢？
The third reason?
我们经常听到或者看到一些令人遗憾的事情。
We often hear or see some regrettable things.
如果当事人。
If the parties.
之前能够做一些信息检索。
I was able to do some information retrieval before.
就可以避免这些悲剧的发生。
You can avoid these tragedies.